<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scientific Python :: Ecosystem Coordination</title>
    <link>https://scientific-python.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Scientific Python :: Ecosystem Coordination</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 11:18:53 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://scientific-python.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning for the Next Decade of Scientific Python</title>
      <link>https://scientific-python.org/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 11:18:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scientific-python.org/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With an extensive and high-quality ecosystem of libraries, scientific Python
has emerged as the leading platform for data analysis.
This ecosystem is sustained by independent volunteers with separate mailing
lists, websites, roadmaps, documentation, engineering and packaging solutions,
and governance structures.
Unfortunately, this also means that there is a lack of coordination that
results in duplicated effort, disorganized documentation, breakage upon new
releases, unintended performance regressions, and user confusion.
Moreover, we have no venue for developing a formal, shared vision
of the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our objective is to prepare scientific Python for the next decade of data science.
To this end, we will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve common engineering infrastructure,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better coordinate core projects,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a community vetted strategic plan, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help the community develop grant proposals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developers of these projects are technically able; but they have little
time to coordinate efforts within their own projects, let alone focus on
strategies for bringing the entire ecosystem together.  This project will
provide support where it is deeply needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;doc/scientific-python-planning-grant-2020.pdf&#34;&gt;full grant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the grant was written pre-COVID-19, we are currently rethinking our
original approach, recruiting the advisory council, and shaping the
initial stage of the grant.  &lt;strong&gt;Watch this space for more, early in
2021!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This work is funded in part by the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation through
grant GBMF8599 to the University of California, Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>